戴尔有时会很烦人
Dale could... could get under your skin.
他反正把我气的够呛
He sure got under mine,
因为他敢于直言自己的想法
because he wasn't afraid to say exactly what he thought,
和感受
how he felt.
那种诚实很珍贵
That kind of honesty is rare,
很勇敢
and brave.
每当我做决定时
Whenever I'd make a decision,
我总是会看着戴尔
I'd look at Dale.
他也会用他的那种表情看着我
He'd be looking back at me with that look he had.
我们都多少见过他那种表情
We've all seen it one time or another.
我有时看不透他  但他却能完全看透我们
I couldn't always read him, but he could read us.
他能看透一个人的本质
He saw people for who they were.
他了解我们...
He knew things about us...
我们的真相...
The truth...
我们的真实自我
Who we really are.
在最后  他还在谈论着丧失人性
In the end, he was talking about losing our humanity.
他说这个队伍散了
He said this group was broken.
致敬他的最好方式就是重新团结起来
The best way to honor him is to unbreak it.
求同存异
Set aside our differences and pull together,
不要再怨天尤人
stop feeling sorry for ourselves,
要掌握我们自己的命运...
and take control of our lives...
我们的安全
Our safety...
我们的未来
our future.
我们没有散
We're not broken.
我们要证明他是错的
We're gonna prove him wrong.
从现在开始...
From now on...
我们要按他的信念行事
we're gonna do it his way.
这就是我们致敬戴尔的方式
That is how we honor Dale.
《行尸走肉》
会很拥挤的  14个人在一间屋子里
It'll be tight, 14 people in one house.
别担心那个
Don't worry about that.
沼泽会冻住  小溪会干涸...
With the swamp hardening, the creek drying up...
加上农场的50头牲畜
With 50 head of cattle on the property,
我们就像行尸的大餐
we might as well be ringing a damn dinner bell.
她说得对
She's right.
我们早该让你们住进来
We should've moved you in a while ago.
好了  我们把车移到每道门前
All right, let's move the vehicles near each of the doors,
-面超着大路  -放那里就行
- facing out toward the road.  - Just leave it there.
我们在风车房和谷仓
We'll build a lookout in the windmill,
设立哨岗  这样视线就能
another in the barn loft. That should give us sightlines
覆盖农场的两边
both sides of the property.
T仔  你在房子周围巡逻
T-Dog, you take the perimeter around the house.
注意每个进出的人
Keep track of everyone coming and going.
那站岗怎么办
What about standing guard?
我需要你和达里尔身兼两份职责
I need you and Daryl on double duty.
明白
Gotcha.
我会在地下室囤积食物和水
I'll stock the basement with food and water,
如果情况糟糕  也足够我们生存几天
enough that we can all survive there a few days if need be.
外围巡逻怎么办  我们先封锁这个区域
What about patrols?Let's get this area locked down first.
然后肖恩分配轮班
After that, Shane'll assign shifts
我和达里尔会把兰德尔带走放生
while me and Daryl take Randall offsite and cut him loose.
我们又要放他
We're back to that now?
本就应该这么做  只怪当时执行不力
It was the right plan first time around.Poor execution.
真是轻描淡写
That's a slight understatement.
就算你不同意  也要这么做
You don't agree, but this what's happening.
给我忍着  然后继续前进
Swallow it. Move on.
你明白戴尔的死和囚犯的事
You know that Dale's death and the prisoner...
是两回事吧
that's two separate things, right?
你想带达里尔去
You wanna take Daryl as your wingman,
随你的便
be my guest.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you.  - You got it.
我明白你为什么不带肖恩
I see why you're not taking Shane with you.
但你要明白只要他在
Just know I've got no more patience
我也不会有多少耐心
where he's concerned.
他会改头换面的
He's turning over a new leaf.
安德莉亚
Andrea.
我和达里尔出去的时候
When I'm out with Daryl,
帮着赫谢尔照看一下这里
help Hershel keep an eye on things around here.
-我吗  -肖恩总喜欢
- Me?  - Shane's got a way
让事情变得失控
of letting things get out of hand,
尤其在他情绪不稳定的时候
especially when he's all torqued up.
我觉得我们现在情绪都不稳定
I think we're all a bit torqued up at this point.
如果他要在这里长住  都就必须明白
If you're staying here permanently, he's got to understand
现在由我和瑞克做主  而不是他为所欲为
that it's what Rick and I say, not whatever he wants.
-你们关系不错  -我们常聊天
- You've become close.  - We talk.
那你就知道他不是坏人
Then you know he's not a bad guy.
他只是自控能力不好
He's just his own worst enemy.
你要我当肖恩的保姆吗
You want me to babysit Shane?
我需要确定每次我离开农场时
I need to make sure every time I leave the farm
事情不会变的一发不可收拾
all hell doesn't break loose.
那么也许你就不应该离开
Then maybe you should stop leaving.
-你能帮我看着这里吗  -当然
- Will you keep an eye on things?  - Of course.
-你好  肖恩  -怎么了  老兄
- Hey, Shane? - What's up, man?
你干嘛呢  一个人在这里乱跑
What you doing, wandering around by yourself?
如果我告诉你一件事情
If, um... If I tell you something,
你能保证不告诉我父母吗
will you promise not to tell my parents?
我觉得这不是个好主意  小家伙
I think it's probably a bad idea for both of us, bud.
卡尔
Hey, Carl.
回来
Come on back.
说吧
Go on.
我从达里尔的摩托上拿的
I took it from Daryl's motorcycle.
如果他发现是我拿的  他会杀了我的
If he found out I took it, he'd kill me.
你拿枪干什么
What you doing with this?
戴尔  他的死是我的错
Dale. It's my fault that he died.
卡尔  你怎么能这样说  他是被行尸杀的
Carl, why would you say that, man? He got bit by a walker.
-你怎么...  -我见过那只行尸
- Why you say...  - I saw that walker.
我本来准备打死它
I was gonna shoot it,
当时他被困在泥里
when he was stuck in the mud.
我朝他身上丢石块
I was... I was throwing rocks at him and stuff.
但我准备做的  我准备把它爆头
But I was gonna do it... shoot it right in the head.
但是它挣脱了泥潭  开始追我...
And it... it got free, came after me and...
我就跑了
I ran away.
如果我杀了它  戴尔就不会死了
If I had killed it, Dale would still be here.
卡尔  你不准再这么说  好吗
Carl, I want you to stop that, okay?
这不是你的错
This ain't your fault.
但是你必须留着这把枪
But you need to hold onto this.
你需要保护自己
You need to protect yourself.
卡尔  只要我在你身边  你就不会有事
As long as I'm around you,nothing's gonna happen to you, Carl.
但我没法每时每刻都罩着你
But I can't keep my eyes on you 24/7.
你得自己照顾自己
Only you can do that.
卡尔  拿着  我再也不碰枪了
Carl, take it.I'm never touching another gun again.
卡尔  这由不得你
That ain't no option, Carl, okay?
把它还给达里尔吧
Just give it back to Daryl.
男人们都在里屋
The men are in there.
你可以把你的东西放我房里
You can put your stuff upstairs in my room.
可是你爸也在家啊
With your dad in the house?
我还是把东西放这儿吧
I just... I'm just gonna put my stuff over there.
当心  别累坏自己了
Whoa. Don't... don't... Don't strain yourself.
谢谢
Thank you.
我  瑞克  卡尔就住客厅角落吧
Rick and Carl and I are taking the corner of the living room.
这东西放我房里去吧
You can put that in my room.
你睡那儿舒服些
You'll be more comfortable there.
那可不行
We can't do that.
我怎能让孕妇和孩子睡地板
A pregnant woman and child sleeping on the floor
自己却睡床上呢
while I've got a bed to myself?
毕竟房子是你的
This is still your house.
现在是大家的了  我在楼下睡沙发吧
It's our home. I'll take the couch downstairs.
以前  我晚上回家时经常浑身酒气
On nights when I came home reeking of bourbon,
我老婆就把我锁在卧室外
my wife would lock the bedroom door.
所以我和沙发是老朋友了
I'm sad to say that couch and I become old friends.
要是你们俩没法决定  可以给我嘛
Look, if you two can't decide, I'll take it.
谢谢
Thank you.
沙发是我的哦
The couch is mine.
睡这屋里肯定舒服多了
It's gonna get real cozy real fast in here.
你怎么不喊别人来帮忙啊
Wouldn't that be easier if you waited for some help?
自己动手  丰衣足食
Ain't no use waiting for something that ain't gonna come.
不必了
No, I'll just...
我自己来就行
Just do it all myself.
是啊  你总这样
Yeah, you always do,
比如那次你大显身手  修好了我家水槽  是啊
just like that time you showed.up Rick fixing our sink.  Yeah.
顺便说句  你家地下室透水是另有原因
Just so you know, that's not the reason your basement flooded.
这你该怪瑞克
You can thank Rick for that...
谁让他铁管里装橡胶圈
Using rubber washers with a metal pipe.
能下来一下吗
Please come down.
索菲亚的事之后
So after Sophia.
我以为我们能重新振作起来
I thought "We'll figure this out."
我们心中的创伤能痊愈
You know, we'll heal somehow.
但是戴尔之后呢
After Dale?
必须面对现实了
This is real.
我们不能
And we can't...
一再逃避了
keep it at bay.
覆水难收
It's already got us.
一波未平一波又起
And it just keeps coming, doesn't it?
我把事情搞得一团糟
I made a mess of things.
我让你和瑞克兄弟反目
I put you and Rick at odds.
我甚至不知道这孩子是谁的
I don't even know whose baby this is.
我无法想象这对你有多难
I can't imagine how hard that is on you.
你不顾自己  带领我们逃离亚特兰大
You led us out of Atlanta with no thought for yourself.
你记得那天晚上吗
Do you remember that night?
城市的熊熊大火
The flames, the...
我坐在你车里
and I'm sitting in our car
想着"我们会平安的"
thinking "We're gonna be all right.
"他会保护我们  我们能逃出去"
He's gonna make it all right. We'll get out of here."
而我却从没说声"谢谢"
And I never thanked you for that.
即使我俩的关系
Even though things got...
变得尴尬
confused between us,
你也一直保护我
you were there for me.
不离不弃  谢谢
You were there for me. Thank you.
你不必说谢谢
You don't need to thank me for that.
-我当然要  当然要  -不用的
- Of course I do. Of course I do.  - No, you...
无论我们之间发生过什么
Whatever happened between us,
无论我们以为拥有什么感情...
whatever the hell we thought it was...
不只你这么以为
and not just you, but...
对不起  肖恩
I'm sorry, Shane.
请相信我  我真心抱歉
Please believe me. I am so sorry.
他到锡诺亚村  来回差不多两小时
Take him out to Senoia... hour there, hour back,
到时候天可能会黑
give or take. We may lose the light,
但也差不多该到家了
but we'll be halfway home by then.
这屁事真是烦死人了
This little pain in the ass will be a distant memory.
解决了就好
Good riddance.
卡萝尔给他备了些干粮
Carol's putting together some provisions for him,
够他吃几天了
enough to last a few days.
昨晚你做的事...
That thing you did last night...
不能每次都让你做难事
Ain't no reason you should do all the heavy lifting.
你对放他走没什么意见吧
So are you good with all this?
我不同意也不反对
I don't see you and I trading haymakers
那场辩论没人赢
on the side of the road. Nobody'd win that fight.
我去撒尿
I'm gonna take a piss.
老兄  你最近和卡尔谈过吗
Hey, man, you seen Carl lately?
他和他妈妈在屋里
He's inside with his mother.
他来找过我
Look, he came to me.
好吧  我原本不该告诉你的
Okay, I wasn't supposed to say anything,
他昨天去了沼泽地
but he was out in the swamps yesterday
发现一只行尸陷在沼泽里
and he came across a walker stuck in the mud.
他害怕  就跑了
He got scared, ran off.
就是杀死戴尔的那只行尸吗
The same walker that killed Dale?
就是那只
That's the one.
我让洛莉跟他谈谈吧
I'll have Lori talk to him.
不  哥们  我觉得
Look, man, I think...
我觉得他是想跟他爹谈
I think he wants to talk to his father.
我得先把兰德尔的事解决了
Well, I need this Randall thing done already.
哥们  那事可以先缓缓
Man, that needs to wait, okay?
这事我说了算
It's my call.
要不我和达里尔去吧
How about I ride out with Daryl?
我和他多相处一下  对大家都好
Good for us to spend a little time together.
不用了  我要你留在这里
Nah, I need you here.
你觉得我办不好这事吗
Don't think I'll handle it right, huh?
-我可没这么说  -那你怎么说
- Didn't say that.  - What you say?
你儿子他
You know, your son...
他给了我这个
He gave me this.
你把它还给达里尔吧
You should get that back to Daryl, huh?
释放那犯人
Freeing that prisoner...
对你来说居然比卡尔更重要
more important to you than Carl.
安德莉亚  你有踩油门吗
Andrea. Hey, did you try pumping the gas pedal?
我觉得是因为太久没开了
I think it's been parked too long.
你得先轻踩三下
You gotta tap it three times...
然后再点火  我知道  我知道
And give her a twist. I know, I know.
让我看看
Let me see.
戴尔教过我 像这种老爷车
Uh, Dale told me that in these old vehicles
总会有些锈蚀
the points get corroded.
要螺丝起子吗
Screwdriver?
要一字起子
Flathead.
把锉刀给我
Could you hand me a file?
我让他失望了
I let him down.
他为你感到骄傲
He was proud of you.
虽然在那一刻不是  但总的来说是骄傲的
Maybe not in that moment, but overall.
你说得倒轻巧
Oh, that's easy for you to say.
你当时支持他的
You had his back.
我也有自己后悔的地方
I have my share of regrets,
但我觉得他心里知道
but I think that he knew
我们有多关心他
how much we cared for him.
车应该能开了
That might do it.
格伦
Glenn.
我猜肯定好了
Bet it'll work.
你妈妈说你会在这里
Mom said you'd be here.
我告诉她我来放哨
Told her I would stand lookout.
我厌倦在屋子那边帮忙了
I got tired of helping around the house.
拿着
Take it.
戴尔身上发生的事情跟你没有任何关系
What happened to Dale had nothing to do with you.
他  他死了  爸爸
He... he died, dad.
对
Yeah.
最近很多人都死了
Feels like there's a lot of that going around.
所以我才需要你
That's why I need you.
我不会再把你当小孩
No more kid stuff.
我希望你能拥有像我一样的童年
I wish you could have the childhood I had,
但这不可能
but that's not gonna happen.
人都会死的
People are gonna die.
我会死  妈妈也是
I'm gonna die. Mom.
你永远无法心情平静的面对死亡
There's no way you can ever be ready for it.
我试着那样去做  但我做不到
I try to be, but I can't.
我们现在能做的就是尽量不去想
The best we can do now is avoid it as long as we can,
活在当下
keep one step ahead.
我希望我能说些更好的话
I wish I had something better to say,
一些  一些深刻的话
something... something more profound.
我的父亲就是那样
My father was good like that.
但是我累了  儿子
But I'm tired, son.
拿着吧
Please take it.
只能弄到这么些箭了
Only got so many arrows.
那是戴尔的枪
Is that Dale's gun?
对
Yeah.
真想知道我的枪在哪
Wish I knew where the hell mine is.
-准备好了  -是的
- Ready?  - Yeah.
-我去拿背包  -谢谢
- I'll get the package.  - Thanks.
嘿  兰迪
Yo, Randy.
管事的说了  可以把你放了
Governor called. You're off the hook.
哦  不
Oh, hell no.
嘘  往那边走
Shh! Go that way.
继续往前走
Go on, go on.
别吭声  别吭声
Shh-shh-shh-shh. Hey-hey, come on. Come on.
我懂  我也许是你最不想见到的人
I get it. I'm the last face you probably want to see, huh?
听着  我会把你从这带走  好吧
Listen, I'm gonna take you up out of here, okay?
我把这个摘下来让你呼吸
I'm gonna get this off of you so you can breathe,
但是你必须保持安静
but I want you to keep quiet.
-你听懂了吗  -嗯
- You listen good. Do you hear me? Okay.  - Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
别做傻事
Don't do nothing stupid.
嘿  安静点
Hey-hey, keep it quiet.
你那群人  你知道他们现在在哪吗
Now your group... you know where they're at?
-我不知道  真的  -好
- No, I don't. I really... oh!  - Okay.
你给我起来  现在我是让你活着
Get your little ass up here. Now I'm the only shot
离开这片树林的唯一机会  你懂吗
of you getting out of these woods alive. You hear me?
现在你说  他们在哪
Now you start talking, boy. Where are they at?
我们在高速旁建了个营地
We had a camp set up off the highway...
-好  -离这里大概5公里远
- Okay.  - About five miles from here.
谁知道他们还在不在那啊
Who knows if they're still there?
好
Okay.
你会带我去找他们是吧
So you gonna take me to 'em?
为什么
Why?
因为  伙计  我
Because, man, I... I'm just...
我受够这帮人了
I'm done with this group, man.
他们迟早完蛋  但是我不想死
They doomed and I want no part of it.
-就是这样  -你不准备杀了我
- That's all.  - So you're not gonna kill me?
如果我想杀你  你现在已经死了
Come on, man. If I was, you'd be dead. Come on.
你不用这么粗暴
Hey, you ain't gotta be so rough.
我们现在在同一战线了
We're on the same side now.
你会喜欢跟我们在一起的
You're gonna like it with us.
有时候会很疯狂
Gets a little crazy sometimes,
但是是很顽强的一群人
but it's a tough bunch of guys.
你会很合群的
You'll fit in good.
少说话  多走路
Less talking, more walking.
当我紧张的时候就会说个不停
Look, I run my mouth when I get nervous.
我控制不住
I can't help it.
我心里事儿很多  懂吗
I got a lot going on, you know?
这事不只跟你有关
It ain't all about you.
我没说跟我有关
I... I ain't saying it's about me.
只是想
Just trying to...
-发生什么了  -兰德尔不见了
- What's wrong?  - Randall's missing.
不见了  怎么可能
Missing? How.
不见多长时间了
How long's he been gone?
-发生什么了  -很难说
- What's goin' on?  - It's hard to say.
手铐还钩在那
The cuffs are still hooked.
-他一定是滑脱的  -那可能吗
- He must' slipped 'em.  - Is that possible?
如果你命悬一线就有可能
It is if you've got nothing to lose.
门是有密码的
The door was secured from the outside.
瑞克  瑞克
Rick! Rick!
-发生什么了  -他有武器
- What happened?  - He's armed!
-他拿了我的枪  -你没事吧
- He's got my gun!  - Are you okay?
我没事  那个混蛋偷袭我
I'm fine. Little bastard just snuck up on me.
-他揍我脸一拳  -赫谢尔  T仔
- He clocked me in the face.  - All right, Hershel, T-Dog,
带所有人回屋子里去
get everybody back in the house.
格伦  达里尔跟我们来
Glenn, Daryl, come with us.
-T仔  我要那把枪  -让他走吧
- T, I'm gonna need that gun.  - Just let him go.
我们就是打算让他走  不是吗
That was the plan, wasn't it, to just let him go?
计划是把他带到远离这儿  再给他松绑
The plan was to cut him loose far away from here,
而不是带着枪  离我们这么近
not on our front step with a gun.
别去那儿  你们知道会发生什么
Don't go out there. Ya'll know what can happen.
带所有人进屋里去
Get everybody back in the house.
把所有门锁上  待着别动
Lock all the doors and stay put!
-我们走  到屋里去  -好的
- Let's go, back in the house.  - Okay.
我晕倒前看到 他沿那条路往树林里跑了
I saw him head up through the trees
他沿那条路往树林里跑了
that way before I blacked out.
我不确定走了多长时间
I'm not sure how long.
他不会走太远
He couldn't have gotten far.
他腿瘸了  精疲力尽
He's hobbled, exhausted.
-而且拿着枪  -我们也是
- And armed. - So are we.
-你能找到他的踪迹吗
- Can you track him?  nothing.
-不能  我什么也没发现
- No, I don't see nothing.
听着  没必要追踪他  好吗
Hey, look, there ain't no use in tracking him, okay?
他朝那个方向去了  我们需要俩俩组队
He went that way. We need to pair up.
我们分头找  追上他  就这么定了
We spread out, we just chase him down. That's it.
那孩子手无缚鸡之力
Kid weighs a buck-25 soaking wet.
你想说是他扑倒了你
You trying to tell us he got the jump on you?
一块石头足够撂倒任何人  你说呢
I say a rock pretty much evens those odds, wouldn't you?
好了  都别说了
Alright, knock it off.
你和格伦去搜右侧
You and Glenn start heading up the right flank.
我和肖恩搜左侧
Me and Shane'll take the left.
外面可不只兰德尔一个威胁
Remember, Randall's not the only threat out there.
互相照应点
Keep an eye out for each other.
你看起来伤的不轻
Looks like it's busted pretty bad.
没事  兄弟
It's fine, man.
别担心我
Don't worry about me.
这样找没用  你有灯么
This is pointless. You got a light?
过来
Come on.
我们又回到起点了
We're just back to square one.
你要是想做件事
If you're gonna do a thing,
不妨把它做对了
you might as well do it right.
这有两道踪迹
There's two sets of tracks right here.
肖恩肯定比他说的跟的远的多
Shane must've followed him a lot longer than he said.
树上有新鲜血迹
There's fresh blood on this tree.
这还有更多踪迹
There's more tracks.
看来像是两人前后走的
Looks like they're walking in tandem.
抱歉
Sorry.
前面这儿有点土
Yeah, there was a little dust up right here.
-什么意思  -有东西摔倒了
- What do you mean?  - I mean something went down.
真是越来越诡异
It's getting weird.
遇到过小麻烦
Had a little trouble.
干得不错
Nice.
这条路对吗
Does this way feel right?
就没错过
As right as any.
-抢了你的枪是吧  -是啊
- Snatched your gun, huh?  - Yeah.
那也是我最喜爱的一把
It's my favorite piece too.
他会希望...
Gonna wish he'd...
我找到他时  他会希望当初杀了我
wish he'd killed me when I find his sorry ass.
继续走
Go on.
天啊  脖子都断了
Got his neck broke.
他身上没有咬痕
He's got no bites.
是啊  看不到
Yeah, none you can see.
对  告诉你死因是这个
No, I'm telling you he died from this.
这怎么可能
How's that possible?
你说他用拿石头砸了你
You say he got you with a rock?
我是这么说
That's what I said.
在棚屋里吗
Inside the shed?
因为T仔说他过去的时候门是锁的
'Cause that door was shut when T-Dog rolled up.
我也看见了
I saw that too.
一定是爬上屋顶的椽木溜出来的
Must've slipped through the rafters in the roof.
所以这就是你打算动手的地方
So this is where you planned to do it?
这是个好地方
It's a good place as any.
至少有胆量叫这什么来着
At least have the balls to call this what it is...
谋杀
Murder.
你真觉得如果你一个人回农场
You really believe if you walk back onto that farm alone...
-我和兰德尔都不见了  -闭嘴
- No me, no Randall...  - I want you to hush up.
你真觉得他们会相信
You really believe they're gonna buy
你编出来的那些狗屁吗
whatever bullshit story you cook up?
这就是事实  不是编的
That's just it. It ain't no story.
我看到那囚犯枪杀了你
I saw that prisoner shoot you down.
我去追他
I ran after him.
然后扭断了他的脖子
I snapped his neck.
虽然不容易
It ain't gonna be easy,
但洛莉和卡尔  他们会放下你的
but Lori and Carl... They'll get over you.
他们放下过一次了
They done it before.
他们必须这样
They just gonna have to.
为什么
Why?
为什么是现在
Why now?
我还以为我们都解决这事了
I thought we worked this all out.
我们那会想要杀死对方啊  兄弟
We tried to kill each other, man.
你想怎样  当这事没发生过
What you think? We just gonna forget about it all?
一起在夕阳下开车兜风
We gonna ride off into the sunset together?
然后冷血地杀了我吗
You're gonna kill me in cold blood?
糟蹋我的妻子
Screw my wife?
让我的孩子们  我的孩子们
Have my children... my children...
喊你爸爸  就是你想要的吗
call you daddy? Is that what you want?
那样的生活一毛不值
That life won't be worth a damn.
我了解你
I know you.
你没法这样活下去
You won't be able to live with this.
对于我能承受多少你知道吗
What you know about what I can live with?
你不知道我能承受什么  承受了什么
You got no idea what I can live with, what I live with!
你想知道我能做到什么  瑞克
You wanna talk about what I can do, Rick?
说说你自己怎样  我就在这
How about what you can do? Here I am.
来啊  兄弟  举起枪
Come on, man. Raise your gun.
-不  我不会  -怎么了  瑞克
- No. No, I will not.  - What happened, Rick?
我还以为你不再是个老好人了
I thought you weren't the good guy anymore.
不是你自己说的吗
Ain't that what you said?
即使此时此地  你也不为他们而战吗
Even right here, right now, you ain't gonna fight for 'em?
我比你更适合做父亲  瑞克
I'm a better father than you, Rick.
我比你更适合与洛莉在一起
I'm better for Lori than you, man.
因为我比你更优秀  瑞克
It's 'cause I'm a better man than you, Rick.
因为我能站在这  为此战斗
'Cause I can be here and I'll fight for it.
你的死而复生毁了一切
You come back here and you just destroy everything!
你妻子失去贞洁
You got a broken woman.
儿子懦弱
You got a weak boy.
怎么处理你毫无头绪
You ain't got the first clue on how to fix it.
举起你的枪
Raise your gun.
你将杀死一个手无寸铁的人
You're gonna have to kill an unarmed man.
看着我的手
Watch my hand.
轻松  简单
Nice and easy.
很容易做到
Easy does it.
听我说  肖恩
Now listen to me, Shane.
现在还能挽回
There is still a way back from this.
当这事没发生过
Nothing has happened here.
我们都放下枪
We're gonna lay down our guns
走回农场
and we're gonna walk back to the farm...
一起
together.
回到洛莉身边
Back to Lori.
回到卡尔身边
Back to Carl.
把这些忘掉
Put this all behind us.
是你逼我这么做的  肖恩
Damn you for making me do this, Shane.
是你  不是我  毁了你我的情谊
This was you, not me! You did this to us!
是你的错  不是我  不是我
This was you, not me... not me!
不是我
Not me!
妈的
Son of...
爸爸
Dad?
卡尔
Carl.
你知道的
You know...
你该回家和你妈在一起
You should be back home with mom.
快放  放下
Just... just put the...
把枪放下
put the gun down.
事情不是这样  拜托
It's not what it seems. Please.
等等  等等
Wait wait wait wait.